faronics.com 2019-02-27

# Privacy Policy - Faronics

**Important**

This is the Privacy Policy of Faronics Corporation and Faronics Pte Ltd. of and other members of its group of companies as listed here:

Faronics Corporation

609 Granville St., Suite 1400

Vancouver, BC  V7Y 1G5

Canada

Faronics Technologies USA Inc.

5506 Sunol Blvd, Suite 202

Pleasanton, CA  94566

United States of America

Faronics Pte. Ltd.

6 Marina Boulevard

#36-22 The Sail At Marina Bay

Singapore, 018985

Singapore

Faronics (EMEA) Ltd.

8 The Courtyard, Eastern Road,

Bracknell, Berkshire,

RG12 2XB, United Kingdom

(the “ **Group** ”).

Where this Privacy Policy refers to “ **Faronics** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”, it is referring to the relevant company within the Group. 

This Privacy Policy explains how Faronics collects, uses and processes your personal data. The notice also provides certain information that is legally required and, where applicable, lists your rights in relation to your personal data.

Our Privacy Policy may be updated by us from time to time. We will provide notice of changes to this Privacy Policy by posting the notice on our website. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it.

If you need to contact us in connection with the use or processing of your personal data, then you can do so at dpo@faronics.com.

## Personal Data

Personal information or personal data means information that by itself identifies an individual (such as name, address, credit card number, telephone number or email address) as well as information that can be combined to identify an individual.  

### How, and the sources from which, we obtain your personal data

We collect personal data from individuals (including individual representatives on  behalf of companies or other legal entities – such as employees, officers or administrators) who express an interest in, register for, or purchase our products either on their own behalf or on behalf of such legal entities, or use our products on their own behalf.  Such individuals may alternatively be acting on behalf of authorized resellers or authorized distributors. In this notice we refer to all of these individuals as “ **Customers** ”).  

Faronics collects personal data in various ways, such as when someone fills out a form on one of our websites, submits an email or other inquiry to us, enters a contest, posts on one of our community forums, registers for, purchases a product or uses a product on their own behalf, or registers or logs on to one of the areas of our websites or web-based applications that are restricted to registered users.

#### How we may use personal data and our basis for using it

This section provides details of the purposes for which we process your personal data, the categories of personal data that we process and, where we are a ‘controller’ within the meaning of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (“ **EU Controller** ”), the legal bases upon which we rely to process your personal data.

Faronics uses  names, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses (“ **Contact Information** ”) and/or credit/debit card numbers, for responding to and processing inquiries and orders. Where we are an EU Controller, our legal basis for doing so is because it is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests in the provision of services as part of our business operations.    

Faronics also may use Contact Information for the purposes of designing and improving our products and services. Where we are an EU Controller, our legal basis for doing so is because it is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests in designing and improving our services as part of our business operations.

Faronics may also use Contact Information for marketing to you, including alerting you to new product offerings as they become available. We will only do this if we have obtained your consent to do so.  In such circumstances we may contact you by post, telephone or e-mail, subject to having received your consent. You will be given the option to stop receiving any communications from us in this regard at any time, however please note that this will not affect us contacting you about the servicing of products that you have specifically requested from us.

Your Contact Information may also be used to provide you with information in connection with your purchases, and to administer your account with us, from time to time. Where we are an EU Controller, our legal basis for doing so is because it is necessary to perform our contract with you.  

Your Contact Information may be used to and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.  Where we are an EU Controller, our legal basis for doing so is because it is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests in enforcing our rights under contracts.

Faronics may also use Contact Information to sell, make ready for sale or dispose of our business in whole or in part including to any potential buyer or their advisers.  Where we are an EU Controller, our legal basis for doing so is because it is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests in the sale or disposal of our business or assets.

## Aggregate Information

We also obtain and use certain aggregated data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose (“ **Aggregate Information** ”). Aggregate Information may be derived from your personal data but does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity and is not personal data. We may use Aggregate Information to improve products, develop new products, understand and/or analyze usage, demand, and general industry trends, develop and publish white papers, reports, and databases summarizing the foregoing, and generally for any purpose related to our business.  We may share Aggregate Information with third parties. Aggregate Information may be derived from information provided by any Customer, from use of our products or from passive data collection techniques described below. This Notice does not restrict or limit our collection and use of Aggregate Information. 

## Where we store your Personal Information

The personal data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our subprocessors. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.  Details of the members of the Group, including where they are based, can be found by under Locations on the Contact Us page of the group website: [https://www.faronics.com/en-uk/company/contact](https://www.faronics.com/company/contact).

## How long we keep your Personal Information 

We keep your personal data only for as long as necessary to delivery products and services to you and for us to meet legal requirements which, in some circumstances, may require us to keep some personal data for an indefinite period. 

Regarding personal data we collect as part of an evaluation of our products and services, we retain the contact information in active systems for a period of up to 1 year after the termination of the evaluation or upon the retraction of consent. Such data may remain resident in backup files or media for up to 1 year after removal.

## How we may share Personal Information 

Faronics will not give, sell, share, or trade any personal information to any party outside of the Group except as outlined in this Privacy Policy or with appropriate consent. We may disclose personal information to a third party in the following circumstances:

  * as needed to enforce Faronics’ Terms of Use, policies and any other contractual relationships with our Customers;
  * when we have a good faith belief that the disclosure is necessary to prevent or respond to fraud, defend our websites or products against possible attacks, or protect the property and safety of Faronics, our Customers or the public;
  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, warrant, regulatory oversight or similar legal process;
  * in connection with any potential sale, transfer, merger, consolidation or other transaction involving all or part of our company;
  * external professional advisers such as accountants, bankers, insurers, auditors and lawyers; 

  * to companies that provide services that help us with our business activities such as processing Customer payments. These companies are authorized to use personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us; and
  * to companies that work with Faronics on various projects; for example, Faronics may share personal information for customer relationship management purposes, email marketing purposes, to our reselling partners.

## Transfers of Personal Information where we are not an EU Controller

Where we are not an EU Controller in respect of your personal data, we may transfer personal data, to countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which the information was initially provided. When we transfer personal information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Notice.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your personal information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

## Cookies and Other Passive Data Collection

### Cookies

Cookies are small text files placed on your device when you visit our Websites. We use cookies to recognize you and your preferences, enhance the performance of our Websites and collect analytical information for the benefit of our business. Our Websites use a mixture of session (which expire with your browser session) and persistent (remain after your browser session expires) cookies to deliver services efficiently and to enhance the experience of using our Websites. The only third-party cookies used by us are analytical/performance cookies such as Google Analytics that gather anonymized information.

We use the following types of cookies for the purposes stated:

#### Strictly necessary cookies

These are cookies that are required for the operation of our websites. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our websites, use a shopping cart or fill in a form.

#### Analytical/performance cookies

These cookies are used to provide us with statistical information about our websites which we use to measure performance and to improve how our websites work. These cookies allow us to recognize and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our websites. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous.

#### Functionality cookies

These cookies are used to recognize you when you return to a website. This enables us to personalize our content for you, tailor our interactions with you and remember your preferences.

By continuing to use our websites you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device. You may block most cookies by activating the settings on your browser that allow you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies you may not be able to access all or parts of our websites. To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

### Other passive data collection from use of websites

We may passively collect such information as device information, log information, browser type, query specifics and Internet Protocol address.  We gather this information through the use of various technologies such as cookies, described above, web beacons (as described below) and other electronic files used to track your navigation of our websites, your completion of transactions and other browsing behavior.  Faronics may use web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to operate and improve our websites and to gather information about usage of our websites and interaction with emails or other electronic communications from Faronics. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your device, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular website tied to the web beacon, and a description of a website tied to the web beacon. Faronics may place web beacons in marketing emails or other electronic messages that notify us when you click on a link in the email that directs you to one of our websites.

### Do Not Track (“DNT”)

Because there is not yet a common industry standard or how to interpret browsers’ DNT signals, Faronics does not currently respond to browser DNT signals when interacting with our websites.

## External Links/Third Party Websites

Faronics’ Websites may provide links to and be accessed via links from third-party websites, including social media websites, whose privacy policies differ from those of Faronics.  Even if the third-party is affiliated with Faronics through a business partnership or otherwise, Faronics is not responsible for the content, privacy policies, or practices of such third-party websites. External links are provided for convenience only and access to these links is at your own risk. We encourage you to review carefully the privacy policy of any web site you may visit.

## Children

Our websites and products are not designed or intended to appeal to minors and we do not knowingly attempt to solicit or receive any information from children. However, if a child under 13 has provided Faronics with personal information, the parent or guardian should contact Faronics immediately at [privacy@faronics.com](mailto:privacy@faronics.com) so we can delete such information from our files.

## Your rights

You have the right to instruct us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. 

Where we are an EU Controller of your personal data, you may have a number of rights in connection with the processing of your personal data, including:

  * the right to request access to your personal data that we process or control;  
  * the right to request rectification of any inaccuracies in your personal data or, taking into account the purposes of our processing, to request that incomplete data is completed; 
  * the right to request, on legitimate grounds as specified in law:

(a) erasure of your personal data that we process or control ; or

(b) restriction of processing of your personal data that we process or control ;

  * the right to object, on legitimate grounds as specified in law, to the processing of your personal data ; 
  * the right to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to have your personal data transferred to another controller, to the extent applicable in law; and
  * the right to lodge complaints regarding the processing of your personal data with the Information Commissioner’s Office  or other relevant supervisory body. Please see https://ico.org.uk/concerns/ for how to do this.

If you would like to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us using the contact details set out in the first section of this Privacy Policy.
